hey everyone welcome back to the stsco
automation playlist and we are talking
about the top 10 tosa best practices now
prior to this I have done five videos on
different best practices so if you not
watched them please go ahead and watch
all those videos before you continue
with this particular
video so before we talk about the tosa
best practice number six I would also
recommend you to subscribe to our
channel so that you don't miss out on
the future
videos so let's jump to this particular
best
practice now tric centus recommends that
we should minimize the use of
Loops now we have seen different loops
and how we can use them in tosa now we
have seen uh do Loop a y Loop and IFL
statement right so we have been using
this uh in some of the scenarios but Tri
scientist tells that Loops are not uh
the natural way of doing things in tosa
the reason is tosa is not a programming
language like Java oret so Java and net
are more suitable for using these Loops
they also have some enhanced versions of
Loops so that they can uh perform better
or more efficiently or faster right but
tosa is just a test automation tool and
it is providing you a way of using the
loops but at the end it is not a
programming language and it cannot
handle the
complexity uh because Loops are complex
to use also they take much longer and
hence they should be
avoided instead of these Loops what
tricentis recommends is to use
constraints or repetion methods so you
will be using Loops whenever you want to
repeat a particular test case a certain
number of times before a condition is
met or you could be also using it um
inside a table where you want to Loop
through all the rows and columns and try
to find some particular cell value right
so these are the scenarios where you'll
be using Loops but instead of that so
instead of going through the loops in
table you can use something like St we
have already seen that and also to
repeat the number of steps u in a
particular test case you can use the
reputations method these two are pretty
straightforward uh methods and they can
be used in these different scenarios now
although we have seen this already uh
since we are talking about this best
practice let me quickly uh go through
the concept uh again
okay so coming back to tosa um let's
look at an example where we have used
the while loop and how it can be avoided
um and instead of that we can use
something called repetion okay so in
this test case you can see there is a
while loop okay what it is doing it is
just setting a buffer uh with a value X
okay so initial value is one for that uh
buffer X and then inside the Y Loop we
are checking whether um that buffer
value is less than five okay okay so
there is a verification step until then
this while loop will continue and inside
the loop what we are doing we are
calculating so we are increasing the
value of the buffer X by one okay so
this will continue until it reaches this
value five and then this condition will
not satisfy so it will stop the loop
okay so that's the whole concept here um
let me quickly run it and show it to you
so here uh we have executed this you can
see uh the buffer has value one and then
the while loop it has got five
reputations and in the last
reputation um the five is less than five
condition is evaluated to false and
hence the repetion stops right so that
all works okay but there is another way
of doing that and even that is much
simpler right again the same thing uh we
set the buffer but then we create a
folder
okay inside this we again do the
calculation okay but here uh in the
properties of this folder we have set
the repetion to five so this will
automatically repeat the steps for five
number of times okay now if I run this
probably the same um action it will
perform it will run the reputations
right so it will set the buffer and then
it will do five repetition okay and then
we will get the buffer value of x
whatever it is right so this is just a
simple example of how you can avoid
Loops in a particular scenario instead
of that use repetition right similarly
if you want to do it in tables right in
web tables when you want to find a
particular cell instead of um going
through all the rows and columns and
then trying to do a comparison of values
and finding that particular set
just put constraints okay so we have put
the constraint on first team and last
team and then um we are verifying that
particular cell okay on which this
constraints are set right so tosa will
go ahead and search for this uh cells
which has got this constraints right and
it will directly end up with this
particular cell uh which matches both
the conditions right so we don't even
need to iterate through all the rows and
columns and make it more complicated
right so the whole idea is to simplify
your test cases right so that it can be
maintained easily and uh they perform
better right and there are less chances
of failure okay so these are the three
ideas which you need to always keep in
mind whenever you are developing your
test cases and use the more efficient
way of U developing them maybe not the
usual way of doing it right so that is
uh what tendus recommends for this
particular best practice minimize the
usage of Loops wherever you can okay you
should only use it at specific places um
otherwise use the more efficient methods
like constraints or
reputations so that's all for this
particular video I hope you enjoyed it
and you liked it uh we would like to
hear your comments so go to the comment
section and put your comments or any
questions you have on this particular
topic we have lots more videos coming up
so keep watching and keep learning